Marijana Ilia Brown

Houston, TX 77006 | mzmarijana@gmail.com | 832-762-5775

DATA. TECHNOLOGY. OPERATIONS

SUMMARY

Forward-thinking futurist, techie visionary and data worshiper - Stellar **15**+ year track record transforming marketing into powerful revenue-driving forces. Rare, powerful combination of strategic business, deep technical, analytical and operational expertise. Expertise in Salesforce Marketing Cloud (SFMC) with a comprehensive understanding of data models, integration, and project lifecycle management.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Extensive experience in digital strategy, web development, marketing technology, data analysis and governance, customer life-cycle and content creation/curation, demand generation, inbound marketing and more...

- Digital Transformation
- Operational Leadership
- Marketing Automation
- SFMC Implementation
- Cloud Integration

- Data Modeling
- Demand Generation
- Email Marketing
- API Integration
- Salesforce Platform

TECHNOLOGY

Salesforce Marketing Cloud | Salesforce | HubSpot | Marketo | Pardot | Google Marketing

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led **8** global digital and data transformation projects, resulting in **\$65M**+ combined savings.
- Launched self-service Digital Center of Excellence (DOE) for developer marketing, enhancing collaboration and learning.
- Generated \$35M+ revenue and increased sales pipeline by 42% through data-driven marketing and automation.
- Led 13 SFMC implementations, 11 database migrations, 10 technical integrations, and more, ensuring seamless project delivery.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Marketing Technology - Assumption Consulting (Remote) 2023 - Present

- Spearheading SFMC implementation projects, ensuring alignment with client objectives.
- Translating business objectives into comprehensive requirements for CRM and marketing automation solutions.
- Leading and participating in the design, configuration, and implementation of SFMC projects.

Marijana Ilia Brown

Houston, TX 77006 | mzmarijana@gmail.com | 832-762-5775

Director of Marketing Automation - TribalVision Consulting (Remote) 2022 - 2023

- Guided a team of technical consultants in various phases of SFMC projects.
- Acted as a liaison between the development team and clients, ensuring effective communication and project success.
- Trained end-users on SFMC applications and facilitated knowledge transfer to new team members.

Director of Digital Marketing - The Linux Foundation (Remote) 2019 - 2021

- Implemented SFMC connect and connected cloud setup, enhancing data integration across platforms.
- Developed proof of concepts to validate technical solutions and ensure client satisfaction.

Digital Marketing Manager - Weatherford International (Houston, TX)2016 - 2018Strategic Marketing Manager - BMC Software, Houston, TX2013 - 2015Sales and Marketing Coordinator - UCB Pharmaceuticals, Smyrna, GA2008 - 2010Communications Specialist - United States Air Force2003 - 2011

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Translated client's business objectives into detailed requirements for CRM and marketing automation functionalities.
- Served as a marketing automation consultant, devising implementation strategies to achieve business objectives.
- Led the design, configuration, and implementation of CRM and marketing automation solutions.
- Led and participated in the design of demand generation and automated marketing campaigns.
- Coordinated with content creation and design resources to ensure HTML assets align with marketing automation best practices.
- Identified and mitigated risks, ensuring project success.
- Acted as a bridge between the development team and the customer, ensuring effective communication.
- Led and mentored new team members to ensure project success.
- Trained end-users on SFMC applications, ensuring seamless adoption.
- Led the integration between marketing tools to assure reliable analytics, data availability, and integrity for reporting.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Communications, Wayne State University, MI | Awarded 2007